<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My Summer as an MP Intern</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025-07-10-mp-intern-summer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025-07-10-mp-intern-summer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently completed my internship for the &lt;strong&gt;Materials Project&lt;/strong&gt; in the &lt;strong&gt;Persson Group&lt;/strong&gt; at &lt;strong&gt;Lawrence Berkeley National Lab&lt;/strong&gt;. This was an incredible experience for me, both as an eager young materials scientist and aspiring software engineer. I got great exposure to the behind-the-scenes operations of a massive, open database and helped develop some pipelines to keep entries up-to-date. Namely, I rebuilt the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/materialsproject/MPCite&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MPCite&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the python package that the team uses to streamline the submission and validation of materials datasets for DOI number allocation, in an orchestrated and parallelized fashion. The package interfaces with the Office of Scientific and Technical Information&amp;rsquo;s ELink API, orchestrates operations with Dagster, parallelizes its workflow with Dask, and queries the internal Materials Project MongoDB database with pymongo.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My name is Hugo. This my website.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am a new grad from &lt;strong&gt;UCLA&lt;/strong&gt; with a &lt;strong&gt;B.S. in Materials Engineering&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;summa cum laude&lt;/em&gt;. While earing this degree, I also explored upper division coursework in Mathematics, Computer Science, and Electrical Engineering. My growing interest in these fields&amp;mdash;coupled with the growing relevancy of computing and data science techniques for materials science&amp;mdash;motivated my current pursuit now of a &lt;strong&gt;M. Eng. in Electrical and Computer Engineering&lt;/strong&gt; at &lt;strong&gt;Cornell Tech&lt;/strong&gt;. Here, I hope to further my understanding in chip design (FPGA and ASIC), ML/AI, and the certain topics fundamental to Operations Research such as linear and non-linear programming and probability theory. On one hand, I am eager to find how I can leverage these concepts to make exciting materials science advancements. On the other hand, I am curious to explore other applications of what I will learn, including high frequency trading algorithms, efficient circuit design, and even healthcare.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
